所以，正如我们现在应该知道的那样，pose有两个组成部分;翻译成分
So, as we should well know by now, pose has got 2 components; a translational component
和旋转部件。我们可以通过几种方式来表现姿势。
and a rotational component. And there are several ways that we can represent a pose.
我们可以将翻译组件表示为向量，然后我们可以表示
We could represent the translational component as a vector, and then we could represent the
旋转分量由一组3个欧拉角组成。或者，我们可以用a代表它
rotational component by a set of 3 Euler angles. Alternatively, we could represent it by a
矢量加上一组3滚，俯仰，偏航角度。或者我们可以将其表示为矢量加
vector plus a set of 3 roll, pitch, yaw angles. Or we could represent it as a vector plus
四元数。第四种选择是将其表示为同质变换
a quaternion. The fourth option is to represent it as a homogeneous transformation and this
是我们为二维案例所做的。正如我们已经多次做过这样的事情
is what we did for the 2-dimensional case. As we've done several times already in this
讲座我们已将概念从二维提升到三维，这就是我们的目标
lecture we've lifted concepts from 2-dimensions in to 3-dimensions and that's what we're going
做下一个。我们将研究如何将姿势描述为均匀变换
to do next. We are going to work out how we describe pose as a homogeneous transformation
在三维。
in 3-dimensions.
考虑两个三维坐标系和一个点P.现在，我将介绍
Consider two 3-dimensional coordinate frames and a point P. Now, I'm going to introduce
一个框架\。它与坐标系B具有相同的原点，但其轴与坐标平行
a frame \. It has the same origin as coordinate frame B but its axes are parallel to coordinate
我可以通过旋转来描述相对于坐标系\的点P，
frame A. I can describe the point P with respect to the coordinate frame \ by using a rotation,
从坐标系\到坐标框架B的旋转。我可以描述框架的原点
rotation from coordinate frame \ to coordinate frame B. I can describe the origin of frame
\通过关于帧A和I的向量可以用向量来描述点P.
\ by a vector with respect to frame A and I can describe the point P in terms of a vector
关于坐标框架A.我可以写一个简单的矢量关系。我可以
with respect to coordinate frame A. I can write a simple vector relationship. I can
添加这两个向量，因为坐标系\的轴与坐标框架A的轴平行。
add these 2 vectors because coordinate frame \ has its axes parallel to those of coordinate frame A.
现在，我可以替换第一个关系，现在我有了一个表达式
Now, I can substitute the first relationship and I have now an expression for a point with
相对于原始坐标系B，相对于帧A的矢量
respect to frame A in terms of a vector with respect to the original coordinate frame B
我可以用A代替\，因为帧\和A的轴彼此平行。
and I can substitute A for \ because the axis of frames \ and A are parallel to each other.
我可以用旋转矩阵的元素替换并按照扩展向量
I can substitute in the elements of the rotation matrix and expand the vectors in terms of
他们的元素，然后，我可以通过在它上面添加1来移动矢量来增加矢量
their elements and then, I can augment the vector by appending a 1 to it and move the
坐标框架的起源到矩阵之间的转换。并保持事情
translation between the origins of the coordinate frames into the matrix. And to keep things
整洁，我将增加另一个向量，这意味着我必须打包矩阵
tidy, I'm going to augment the other vector as well which means I have to pack the matrix
用一些零和一些。所以，我们现在拥有的是同质的代表。
out with some zeroes and ones. So, what we have now is a homogeneous representation.
我们有一个齐次变换矩阵和两个齐次向量。我们可以写
We have a homogeneous transformation matrix and two homogeneous vectors. We can write
它以紧凑的形式像这样注意通过放置一个同类向量
it in compact form like this with the note that the homogeneous vectors by putting a
在他们上方。我们可以看到该矩阵包括旋转分量，即平移
tilde above them. We can see that this matrix comprises a rotation component, a translational
组件，3个零和一个。
component, 3 zeroes and a one.
因此，这个单独的4x4矩阵封装了旋转和平移，并允许我们使用
So, this single 4 x 4 matrix encapsulates rotation and translation and allows us to
变换描述从坐标系B到坐标系A的点的向量。
transform a vector describing a point from coordinate frame B to coordinate frame A.
这里的这个4x4矩阵，我们称为均匀变换和这两个矢量
This 4 x 4 matrix here, we refer to as a homogeneous transformation and these 2 vectors
这里是同类向量。只是提醒同类矢量，我们用它来表示它们
here are homogeneous vectors. And just a reminder on homogeneous vectors, we denote them by
在顶部。我们采用笛卡尔向量，在这种情况下因为它是三维空间，
tilde on top. We take the Cartesian vector, in this case because it's 3-dimensional space,
它有3个元素A，B和C.它的同类版本有4个元素A，B，C
it's got 3 elements A, B and C. The homogeneous version of that has got 4 elements A, B, C
我们在它上面添加1。这是一个非常紧凑的形式。我们有一个观点
and 1. We append a 1 to it. Here it is in a very compact form. We have a point denoted
通过关于帧B的均匀向量，我们可以将其转换为所描述的点
by a homogeneous vector with respect to frame B and we can transform it to a point described
通过相对于帧A的均匀矢量。相对姿势由单个4描述
A. Relative pose is described by single 4
x4矩阵。数学家会说这个矩阵属于特殊的欧几里德
x 4 matrix. A mathematician would say that this matrix belongs to the special Euclidean
维度3的组和简写的是T是集合SE（3）的元素;3表明
group of dimension 3 and the short hand is that T is an element of the set SE(3); 3 indicating
这种情况下的维度3。
the dimension in this case 3.
我们可以使用齐次变换矩阵，而不是抽象符号ksi
Instead of the abstract symbol ksi, we can use a homogeneous transformation matrix, a
4x4矩阵。配混或组合物仅仅是基质-基质产品。复合
4 x 4 matrix. Compounding or composition is simply a matrix-matrix product. To compound
2个姿势，我简单地在均匀变换方面将它们的表示相乘。注意
2 poses, I simply multiply their representation in terms of homogeneous transformations. Note
以及均匀变换的倒数不等于它的转置，即该属性
well that the inverse of a homogeneous transformation is not equal to its transpose, that property
仅属于矩阵的旋转分量，矩阵是正交矩阵。该
only belongs to the rotational component of a matrix which is an orthogonal matrix. The
均匀变换矩阵不是正交矩阵。它的反面并不相等
homogeneous transformation matrix is not an orthogonal matrix. It's inverse is not equal
它的转置。最后，矢量变换只是一个矩阵矢量积。
to its transpose. Finally, vector transformation is simply a matrix-vector product.